<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SSL on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/tags/ssl/</link><description>Recent content in SSL on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Toni Schmidbauer &amp; Thomas Jungbauer</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 04:35:17 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.stderr.at/tags/ssl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OpenShift</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/</guid><description/></item><item><title>SSL Certificate Management for OpenShift on AWS</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2023/02/ssl-certificate-management-for-openshift-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2023/02/ssl-certificate-management-for-openshift-on-aws/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Finally, after a long time on my backlog, I had some time to look into the &lt;strong>Cert-Manager Operator&lt;/strong> and use this Operator to automatically issue new SSL certificates.
This article shall show step-by-step how to create a certificate request and use this certificate for a Route and access a service via your Browser.
I will focus on the technical part, using a given domain on AWS Route53.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>YAUB Yet Another Useless Blog</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/</guid><description>&lt;h1 class="blog-title gradient-header">Welcome to Yet Another Useless Blog&lt;/h1>


&lt;p>Well we hope the articles here are not totally useless :)&lt;/p>

&lt;p>Who are we, you might ask.
We (Thomas Jungbauer and Toni Schmidbauer) are two old IT guys, working in the business since more than 20 years. At the moment we are architects at Red Hat Austria, mainly responsible helping customers with OpenShift or Ansible architectures. &lt;/p>

&lt;p>The articles in this blog shall help to easily test and understand specific issues so they can be reproduced and tested. We simply wrote down what we saw in the field and of what we thought it might be helpful, so no frustrating searches in documentations or manual testing is required. &lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>