<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/tags/security/</link><description>Recent content in Security on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Toni Schmidbauer &amp; Thomas Jungbauer</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 09:34:20 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.stderr.at/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Compliance</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/compliance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/compliance/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Advanced Cluster Security</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/acs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/acs/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Introducing AdminNetworkPolicies</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2024/11/introducing-adminnetworkpolicies/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2024/11/introducing-adminnetworkpolicies/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Classic Kubernetes/OpenShift offer a feature called NetworkPolicy that allows users to control the traffic to and from their assigned Namespace.
NetworkPolicies are designed to give project owners or tenants the ability to protect their own namespace. Sometimes, however, I worked with customers where the
cluster administrators or a dedicated (network) team need to enforce these policies.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Since the NetworkPolicy API is namespace-scoped, it is not possible to enforce policies across namespaces. The only solution was to create custom (project) admin and edit
roles, and remove the ability of creating, modifying or deleting NetworkPolicy objects. Technically, this is possible and easily done. But shifts the whole network security to cluster administrators.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Luckily, this is where &lt;strong>AdminNetworkPolicy&lt;/strong> (ANP) and &lt;strong>BaselineAdminNetworkPolicy&lt;/strong> (BANP) comes into play.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Advanced Cluster Security - Authentication</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/acs/2021-12-11-acsauth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/acs/2021-12-11-acsauth/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Red Hat Advanced Cluster Security (RHACS) Central is installed with one administrator user by default. Typically, customers request an integration with existing Identity Provider(s) (IDP). RHACS offers different options for such integration. In this article 2 IDPs will be configured as an example. First OpenShift Auth and second Red Hat Single Sign On (RHSSO) based on Keycloak&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>oc compliance command line plugin</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/compliance/2021/07/oc-compliance-command-line-plugin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/compliance/2021/07/oc-compliance-command-line-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>As described at &lt;a href="https://blog.stderr.at/compliance/2021/07/compliance-operator/">Compliance Operator&lt;/a> the Compliance Operator can be used to scan the OpenShift cluster environment against security benchmark, like CIS.
Fetching the actual results might be a bit tricky tough.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>With OpenShift 4.8 plugins to the &lt;code>oc&lt;/code> command are allowed. One of these plugin os &lt;code>oc compliance&lt;/code>, which allows you to easily fetch scan results, re-run scans and so on.
Let’s install and try it out.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Compliance Operator</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/compliance/2021/07/compliance-operator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/compliance/2021/07/compliance-operator/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>OpenShift comes out of the box with a highly secure operating system, called Red Hat CoreOS. This OS is immutable, which means that no direct changes are done inside the OS, instead any configuration is managed by OpenShift itself using MachineConfig objects. Nevertheless, hardening certain settings must still be considered. Red Hat released a hardening guide (CIS Benchmark) which can be downloaded at &lt;a href="https://www.cisecurity.org/" class="bare">https://www.cisecurity.org/&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Authorization (RBAC)</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/service-mesh/2020/05/authorization-rbac/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/service-mesh/2020/05/authorization-rbac/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Per default all requests inside a Service Mesh are allowed, which can be a problem security-wise.
To solve this, authorization, which verifies if the user is allowed to perform a certain action, is required.
Istio’s authorization provides access control on mesh-level, namespace-level and workload-level.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>YAUB Yet Another Useless Blog</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/</guid><description>Welcome to Yet Another Useless Blog Well we hope the articles here are not totally useless :)
Who are we, you might ask. We (Thomas Jungbauer and Toni Schmidbauer) are two old IT guys, working in the business since more than 20 years. At the moment we are architects at Red Hat Austria, mainly responsible helping customers with OpenShift or Ansible architectures. The articles in this blog shall help to easily test and understand specific issues so they can be reproduced and tested.</description></item></channel></rss>