<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rekor on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/tags/rekor/</link><description>Recent content in Rekor on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Toni Schmidbauer &amp; Thomas Jungbauer</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 16:19:40 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.stderr.at/tags/rekor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Secure Supply Chain</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/securesupplychain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/securesupplychain/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Introduction to a Secure Supply Chain</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/securesupplychain/2023-06-15-securesupplychain-intro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/securesupplychain/2023-06-15-securesupplychain-intro/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>The goal of the following (&amp;#34;short&amp;#34;) series is to build a secure CI/CD pipeline step by step using OpenShift Pipelines (based on Tekton).
The whole build process shall pull and build an image, upload it to a development environment and subsequently update the production environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>The main focus here is security. Several steps and tools shall help to build and deploy a &lt;strong>Secure Supply Chain&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>The whole process is part of a Red Hat workshop which can present to your organization. I did some tweaks and created a step-by-step plan in order
to remember it …​ since I am getting old :)&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Step 12 - Verify TLog Signature</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/securesupplychain/2023-06-27-securesupplychain-step12/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/securesupplychain/2023-06-27-securesupplychain-step12/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Since the image has been deployed on DEV now, we need to prepare everything for production. Before we start, we need to confirm that the whole signing process has been passed and that our signature has been applied correctly. With CoSign we signed our image and used Rekor to create a transparency log. We will use this log to confirm that the image was signed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Step 13 - Bring it to Production</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/securesupplychain/2023-06-28-securesupplychain-step13/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/securesupplychain/2023-06-28-securesupplychain-step13/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>If you reached this article, congratulations! You read through tons of pages to build up a Pipeline. The last two steps in our Pipeline are: Creating a new branch and creating a pull request, with the changes of the image tag that must be approved and will be merged then (We will not update the main branch directly!). Finally, we will do a &amp;#34;real&amp;#34; update to the application to see the actual changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>YAUB Yet Another Useless Blog</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/</guid><description>Welcome to Yet Another Useless Blog Well we hope the articles here are not totally useless :)
Who are we, you might ask. We (Thomas Jungbauer and Toni Schmidbauer) are two old IT guys, working in the business since more than 20 years. At the moment we are architects at Red Hat Austria, mainly responsible helping customers with OpenShift or Ansible architectures. The articles in this blog shall help to easily test and understand specific issues so they can be reproduced and tested.</description></item></channel></rss>