<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Storage on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/tags/storage/</link><description>Recent content in Storage on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Toni Schmidbauer &amp; Thomas Jungbauer</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 15:10:12 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.stderr.at/tags/storage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OpenShift</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Installing OpenShift Logging using GitOps</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/2024-05-24-install-openshift-logging/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/2024-05-24-install-openshift-logging/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://docs.openshift.com/container-platform/4.15/observability/logging/logging_release_notes/logging-5-9-release-notes.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OpenShift Logging&lt;/a> is one of the more complex things to install and configure on an OpenShift cluster. Not because the service or Operators are so complex to understand, but because of the dependencies logging has. Besides the logging operator itself, the Loki operator is required, the Loki operator requires access to an object storage, that might be configured or is already available.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>In this article, I would like to demonstrate the configuration of the full stack using an object storage from OpenShift Data Foundation. This means:&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="ulist">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Installing the logging operator into the namespace openshift-logging&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Installing the Loki operator into the namespace openshift-operators-redhat&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Creating a new BackingStore and BucketClass&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Generating the Secret for Loki to authenticate against the object storage&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Configuring the LokiStack resource&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Configuring the ClusterLogging resource&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>All steps will be done automatically. In case you have S3 storage available, or you are not using OpenShift Data Foundation, the setup will be a bit different. For example, you do not need to create a BackingStore or the Loki authentication Secret.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Configure Buckets in MinIO using GitOps</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/2024-05-17-configure-minio-buckets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/2024-05-17-configure-minio-buckets/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://min.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MinIO&lt;/a> is a simple, S3-compatible object storage, built for high-performance and large-scale environments. It can be installed as an Operator to Openshift. In addition, to a command line tool, it provides a WebUI where all settings can be done, especially creating and configuring new buckets. Currently, this is not possible in a declarative GitOps-friendly way.
Therefore, I created the Helm chart &lt;a href="https://github.com/tjungbauer/helm-charts/tree/main/charts/minio-configurator" target="_blank" rel="noopener">minio configurator&lt;/a>, that will start a Kubernetes Job, which will take care of the configuration.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Honestly, when I say I have created it, the truth is, that it is based on an existing &lt;a href="https://github.com/bitnami/charts/tree/main/bitnami/minio" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MinIO Chart by Bitnami&lt;/a>, that does much more than just set up a bucket. I took out the bucket configuration part, streamlined it a bit and added some new features, which I required.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>This article shall explain how to achieve this.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Secure your secrets with Sealed Secrets</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2021/09/secure-your-secrets-with-sealed-secrets/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2021/09/secure-your-secrets-with-sealed-secrets/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Working with a GitOps approach is a good way to keep all configurations and settings versioned and in sync on Git. Sensitive data, such as passwords to a database connection, will quickly come around.
Obviously, it is not a idea to store clear text strings in a, maybe even public, Git repository. Therefore, all sensitive information should be stored in a secret object. The problem with secrets in Kubernetes is that they are actually not encrypted. Instead, strings are base64 encoded which can be decoded as well. Thats not good …​ it should not be possible to decrypt secured data. Sealed Secret will help here…​&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Understanding RWO block device handling in OpenShift</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2021/02/understanding-rwo-block-device-handling-in-openshift/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2021/02/understanding-rwo-block-device-handling-in-openshift/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>In this blog post we would like to explore OpenShift / Kubernetes
block device handling. We try to answer the following questions:&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="ulist">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>What happens if multiple pods try to access the same block device?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>What happens if we scale a deployment using block devices to more than one replica?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>YAUB Yet Another Useless Blog</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/</guid><description>&lt;h1 class="blog-title gradient-header">Welcome to Yet Another Useless Blog&lt;/h1>


&lt;p>Well we hope the articles here are not totally useless :)&lt;/p>

&lt;p>Who are we, you might ask.
We (Thomas Jungbauer and Toni Schmidbauer) are two old IT guys, working in the business since more than 20 years. At the moment we are architects at Red Hat Austria, mainly responsible helping customers with OpenShift or Ansible architectures. &lt;/p>

&lt;p>The articles in this blog shall help to easily test and understand specific issues so they can be reproduced and tested. We simply wrote down what we saw in the field and of what we thought it might be helpful, so no frustrating searches in documentations or manual testing is required. &lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>