<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Affinity on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/tags/affinity/</link><description>Recent content in Affinity on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Toni Schmidbauer &amp; Thomas Jungbauer</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 17:46:24 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.stderr.at/tags/affinity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pod Placement</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/day-2/pod-placement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/day-2/pod-placement/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/day-2/pod-placement/2021-08-26-podplacement-intro/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/day-2/pod-placement/2021-08-26-podplacement-intro/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Pod scheduling is an internal process that determines placement of new pods onto nodes within the cluster. It is probably one of the most important tasks for a Day-2 scenario and should be considered at a very early stage for a new cluster. OpenShift/Kubernetes is already shipped with a &lt;strong>default scheduler&lt;/strong> which schedules pods as they get created accross the cluster, without any manual steps.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>However, there are scenarios where a more advanced approach is required, like for example using a specifc group of nodes for dedicated workload or make sure that certain applications do not run on the same nodes. Kubernetes provides different options:&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="ulist">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Controlling placement with node selectors&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Controlling placement with pod/node affinity/anti-affinity rules&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Controlling placement with taints and tolerations&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Controlling placement with topology spread constraints&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>This series will try to go into the detail of the different options and explains in simple examples how to work with pod placement rules.
It is not a replacement for any official documentation, so always check out Kubernetes and or OpenShift documentations.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Node Affinity</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/day-2/pod-placement/2021-08-29-node-affinity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/day-2/pod-placement/2021-08-29-node-affinity/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Node Affinity allows to place a pod to a specific group of nodes. For example, it is possible to run a pod only on nodes with a specific CPU or disktype. The disktype was used as an example for the &lt;code>nodeSelector&lt;/code> and yes …​ Node Affinity is conceptually similar to nodeSelector but allows a more granular configuration.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Pod Affinity/Anti-Affinity</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/day-2/pod-placement/2021-08-28-affinity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/day-2/pod-placement/2021-08-28-affinity/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>While noteSelector provides a very easy way to control where a pod shall be scheduled, the affinity/anti-affinity feature, expands this configuration with more expressive rules like logical AND operators, constraints against labels on other pods or soft rules instead of hard requirements.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>The feature comes with two types:&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="ulist">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>pod affinity/anti-affinity - allows constrains against other pod labels rather than node labels.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>node affinity - allows pods to specify a group of nodes they can be placed on&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>YAUB Yet Another Useless Blog</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/</guid><description>&lt;h1 class="blog-title gradient-header">Welcome to Yet Another Useless Blog&lt;/h1>


&lt;p>Well we hope the articles here are not totally useless :)&lt;/p>

&lt;p>Who are we, you might ask.
We (Thomas Jungbauer and Toni Schmidbauer) are two old IT guys, working in the business since more than 20 years. At the moment we are architects at Red Hat Austria, mainly responsible helping customers with OpenShift or Ansible architectures. &lt;/p>

&lt;p>The articles in this blog shall help to easily test and understand specific issues so they can be reproduced and tested. We simply wrote down what we saw in the field and of what we thought it might be helpful, so no frustrating searches in documentations or manual testing is required. &lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>