<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/categories/security/</link><description>Recent content in Security on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Toni Schmidbauer &amp; Thomas Jungbauer</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 18:05:24 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.stderr.at/categories/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setup &amp; Configure Compliance Operator using GitOps</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/2024-04-25-installing-compliance-operator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/2024-04-25-installing-compliance-operator/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>In the previous articles, we have discussed the &lt;a href="https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/2023-12-28-gitops-repostructure/">Git repository folder structure&lt;/a> and the configuration of the &lt;a href="gitopscollection/2024-04-02-configure_app_of_apps/">App-Of-Apps&lt;/a>. Now it is time to deploy our first configuration. One of the first things I usually deploy is the &lt;a href="https://docs.openshift.com/container-platform/4.15/security/compliance_operator/co-overview.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Compliance Operator&lt;/a>. This Operator is recommended for any cluster and can be deployed without any addition to the Subscription.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>In this article, I will describe how it is installed and how the Helm Chart is configured.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Secrets Management - Vault on OpenShift</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2022/08/secrets-management-vault-on-openshift/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2022/08/secrets-management-vault-on-openshift/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Sensitive information in OpenShift or Kubernetes is stored as a so-called Secret. The management of these Secrets is one of the most important questions,
when it comes to OpenShift. Secrets in Kubernetes are encoded in base64. This is &lt;strong>not&lt;/strong> an encryption format.
Even if etcd is encrypted at rest, everybody can decode a given base64 string which is stored in the Secret.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>For example: The string &lt;code>Thomas&lt;/code> encoded as base64 is &lt;code>VGhvbWFzCg==&lt;/code>. This is simply a masked plain text and it is not secure to share these values, especially not on Git.
To make your CI/CD pipelines or Gitops process secure, you need to think of a secure way to manage your Secrets. Thus, your Secret objects must be encrypted somehow. HashiCorp Vault is one option to achieve this requirement.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Automated ETCD Backup</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/day-2/etcd/2022-01-29-automatedetcdbackup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/day-2/etcd/2022-01-29-automatedetcdbackup/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Securing ETCD is one of the major Day-2 tasks for a Kubernetes cluster. This article will explain how to create a backup using OpenShift Cronjob.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Advanced Cluster Security - Authentication</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/acs/2021-12-11-acsauth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/acs/2021-12-11-acsauth/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Red Hat Advanced Cluster Security (RHACS) Central is installed with one administrator user by default. Typically, customers request an integration with existing Identity Provider(s) (IDP). RHACS offers different options for such integration. In this article 2 IDPs will be configured as an example. First OpenShift Auth and second Red Hat Single Sign On (RHSSO) based on Keycloak&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Secure your secrets with Sealed Secrets</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2021/09/secure-your-secrets-with-sealed-secrets/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2021/09/secure-your-secrets-with-sealed-secrets/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Working with a GitOps approach is a good way to keep all configurations and settings versioned and in sync on Git. Sensitive data, such as passwords to a database connection, will quickly come around.
Obviously, it is not a idea to store clear text strings in a, maybe even public, Git repository. Therefore, all sensitive information should be stored in a secret object. The problem with secrets in Kubernetes is that they are actually not encrypted. Instead, strings are base64 encoded which can be decoded as well. Thats not good …​ it should not be possible to decrypt secured data. Sealed Secret will help here…​&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>oc compliance command line plugin</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/compliance/2021/07/oc-compliance-command-line-plugin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/compliance/2021/07/oc-compliance-command-line-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>As described at &lt;a href="https://blog.stderr.at/compliance/2021/07/compliance-operator/">Compliance Operator&lt;/a> the Compliance Operator can be used to scan the OpenShift cluster environment against security benchmark, like CIS.
Fetching the actual results might be a bit tricky tough.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>With OpenShift 4.8 plugins to the &lt;code>oc&lt;/code> command are allowed. One of these plugin os &lt;code>oc compliance&lt;/code>, which allows you to easily fetch scan results, re-run scans and so on.
Let’s install and try it out.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Compliance Operator</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/compliance/2021/07/compliance-operator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/compliance/2021/07/compliance-operator/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>OpenShift comes out of the box with a highly secure operating system, called Red Hat CoreOS. This OS is immutable, which means that no direct changes are done inside the OS, instead any configuration is managed by OpenShift itself using MachineConfig objects. Nevertheless, hardening certain settings must still be considered. Red Hat released a hardening guide (CIS Benchmark) which can be downloaded at &lt;a href="https://www.cisecurity.org/" class="bare">https://www.cisecurity.org/&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>