<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>oc on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/tags/oc/</link><description>Recent content in oc on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Toni Schmidbauer &amp; Thomas Jungbauer</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.stderr.at/tags/oc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OpenShift</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Operator installation with Argo CD</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2023-03-20-operator-installation-with-argocd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2023-03-20-operator-installation-with-argocd/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>GitOps for application deployment and cluster configuration is a must-have I am trying to convince every customer to follow from the very beginning when starting the Kubernetes journey. For me, as more on the infrastructure side of things, I am more focused on the configuration of an environment.
Meaning, configuring a cluster, installing an operator etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>In this article, I would like to share how I deal with cluster configuration when certain Kubernetes objects are dependent on each other and how to use Kubernetes but also Argo CD features to resolve these dependencies.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>SSL Certificate Management for OpenShift on AWS</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2023-02-16-ssl-certificate-management/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2023-02-16-ssl-certificate-management/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Finally, after a long time on my backlog, I had some time to look into the &lt;strong>Cert-Manager Operator&lt;/strong> and use this Operator to automatically issue new SSL certificates.
This article shall show step-by-step how to create a certificate request and use this certificate for a Route and access a service via your Browser.
I will focus on the technical part, using a given domain on AWS Route53.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Using ServerSideApply with ArgoCD</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2022-11-04-argocd-and-serversideapply/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2022-11-04-argocd-and-serversideapply/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>„&lt;em>If it is not in GitOps, it does not exist&lt;/em>“ - However, managing objects partially only by Gitops was always an issue, since ArgoCD would like to manage the whole object. For example, when you tried to work with node labels and would like to manage them via Gitops, you would need to put the whole node object into ArgoCD. This is impractical since the node object is very complex and typically managed by the cluster.
There were 3rd party solutions (like the patch operator), that helped with this issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>However, with the Kubernetes feature &lt;strong>Server-Side Apply&lt;/strong> this problem is solved. Read further to see a working example of this feature.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Helpful oc / kubectl commands</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2020-04-01-oc-commands/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2020-04-01-oc-commands/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>This is a list of useful oc and/or kubectl commands so they won’t be forgotton. No this is not a joke…​&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>YAUB Yet Another Useless Blog</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/</guid><description>Welcome to YAUB - Yet Another Useless Blog The articles in this blog shall help to easily test and understand specific issues so they can be reproduced and tested on local environments.
You can find the most recent posts on this site or walk through the different categories via the left navigation.</description></item></channel></rss>