<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NodeSelector on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/tags/nodeselector/</link><description>Recent content in NodeSelector on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Toni Schmidbauer &amp; Thomas Jungbauer</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.stderr.at/tags/nodeselector/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Labels &amp; Environments</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/day-2/labels_environmets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/day-2/labels_environmets/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Pod Placement</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/day-2/pod-placement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/day-2/pod-placement/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Working with Environments</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/day-2/labels_environmets/2022-01-12-creatingenvironment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/day-2/labels_environmets/2022-01-12-creatingenvironment/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Imagine you have one OpenShift cluster and you would like to create 2 or more environments inside this cluster, but also separate them and force the environments to specific nodes, or use specific inbound routers. All this can be achieved using labels, IngressControllers and so on. The following article will guide you to set up dedicated compute nodes for infrastructure, development and test environments as well as the creation of IngressController which are bound to the appropriate nodes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/day-2/pod-placement/2021-08-26-podplacement-intro/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/day-2/pod-placement/2021-08-26-podplacement-intro/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Pod scheduling is an internal process that determines placement of new pods onto nodes within the cluster. It is probably one of the most important tasks for a Day-2 scenario and should be considered at a very early stage for a new cluster. OpenShift/Kubernetes is already shipped with a &lt;strong>default scheduler&lt;/strong> which schedules pods as they get created accross the cluster, without any manual steps.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>However, there are scenarios where a more advanced approach is required, like for example using a specifc group of nodes for dedicated workload or make sure that certain applications do not run on the same nodes. Kubernetes provides different options:&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="ulist">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Controlling placement with node selectors&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Controlling placement with pod/node affinity/anti-affinity rules&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Controlling placement with taints and tolerations&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Controlling placement with topology spread constraints&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>This series will try to go into the detail of the different options and explains in simple examples how to work with pod placement rules.
It is not a replacement for any official documentation, so always check out Kubernetes and or OpenShift documentations.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>NodeSelector</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/day-2/pod-placement/2021-08-27-podplacement/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/day-2/pod-placement/2021-08-27-podplacement/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>One of the easiest ways to tell your Kubernetes cluster where to put certain pods is to use a &lt;code>nodeSelector&lt;/code> specification. A nodeSelector defines a key-value pair and are defined inside the specification of the pods and as a label on one or multiple nodes (or machine set or machine config). Only if selector matches the node label, the pod is allowed to be scheduled on that node.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>YAUB Yet Another Useless Blog</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/</guid><description>Welcome to YAUB - Yet Another Useless Blog The articles in this blog shall help to easily tests and understand specific issues so they can be reproduced and tested on local environments.
You can find the most recent posts on this site or walk through the different categories via the left navigation.</description></item></channel></rss>