<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GitOps Episodes on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/</link><description>Recent content in GitOps Episodes on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Toni Schmidbauer &amp; Thomas Jungbauer</copyright><atom:link href="https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setup OpenShift GitOps/Argo CD</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/2024-02-02-setup-argocd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/2024-02-02-setup-argocd/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>„&lt;em>If it is not in GitOps, it does not exist&lt;/em>“ - is a mantra I hear quite often and also try to practice at customer engagements. The idea is to have Git as the only source of truth on what happens inside the environment. That said, &lt;a href="https://openpracticelibrary.com/practice/everything-as-code/">Everything as Code&lt;/a> is a practice that treats every aspect of the system as a code. Storing this code in Git provides a shared understanding, traceability and repeatability of changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>While there are many articles about how to get GitOps into the deployment process of applications, this one rather sets the focus on the &lt;strong>cluster configuration&lt;/strong> and tasks system administrators usually have to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>GitOps - Choosing the right Git repository structure</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/2023-12-28-gitops-repostructure/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/2023-12-28-gitops-repostructure/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>One of the most popular questions asked before adopting the GitOps approach is how to deploy an application to different environments (Test, Dev, Production, etc.) in a safe and repeatable way.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Each organisation has different requirements, and the choice will depend on a multitude of factors that also include non-technical aspects.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Therefore, it is important to state: &amp;#34;&lt;strong>There is no unique “right” way, there are common practices&lt;/strong>&amp;#34;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Introducing the GitOps Approach</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/2023-12-11-gitops-intro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/2023-12-11-gitops-intro/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>When managing one or more clusters, the question arises as to how cluster configurations and applications can be installed securely, regularly, and in the same way.
This is where the so-called GitOps approach helps, according to the mantra: &amp;#34;&lt;strong>If it is not in Git, it does not exist&lt;/strong>&amp;#34;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>The idea is to have Git as the only source of truth on what happens inside the environment. While there are many articles about how to get GitOps into the deployment process of applications, this series of articles tries to set the focus on the &lt;strong>cluster configuration&lt;/strong> and tasks system administrators usually have to do, for example: Setup an Operator.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>