<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GitOps on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/tags/gitops/</link><description>Recent content in GitOps on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Toni Schmidbauer &amp; Thomas Jungbauer</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.stderr.at/tags/gitops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GitOps Episodes</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/</guid><description/></item><item><title>OpenShift</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Configure App-of-Apps</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/2024-04-02-configure_app_of_apps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/2024-04-02-configure_app_of_apps/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>In the article &lt;a href="https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/2024-02-02-setup-argocd/">Install GitOps to the cluster&lt;/a> OpenShift GitOps is deployed using a shell script. This should be the very first installation and the only deployment that is done manually on a cluster. This procedure automatically installs the so-called &lt;strong>App-of-Apps&lt;/strong> named &lt;strong>Argo CD Resources Manager&lt;/strong> which is responsible for all further Argo CD Applications and ApplicationSets. No other configuration should be done manually if possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>This article will demonstrate how to configure the App-of-Apps in an easy and declarative way, using ApplicationSet mainly.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Setup OpenShift GitOps/Argo CD</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/2024-02-02-setup-argocd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/2024-02-02-setup-argocd/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>„&lt;em>If it is not in GitOps, it does not exist&lt;/em>“ - is a mantra I hear quite often and also try to practice at customer engagements. The idea is to have Git as the only source of truth on what happens inside the environment. That said, &lt;a href="https://openpracticelibrary.com/practice/everything-as-code/">Everything as Code&lt;/a> is a practice that treats every aspect of the system as a code. Storing this code in Git provides a shared understanding, traceability and repeatability of changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>While there are many articles about how to get GitOps into the deployment process of applications, this one rather sets the focus on the &lt;strong>cluster configuration&lt;/strong> and tasks system administrators usually have to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>GitOps - Choosing the right Git repository structure</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/2023-12-28-gitops-repostructure/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/2023-12-28-gitops-repostructure/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>One of the most popular questions asked before adopting the GitOps approach is how to deploy an application to different environments (Test, Dev, Production, etc.) in a safe and repeatable way.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Each organisation has different requirements, and the choice will depend on a multitude of factors that also include non-technical aspects.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Therefore, it is important to state: &amp;#34;&lt;strong>There is no unique “right” way, there are common practices&lt;/strong>&amp;#34;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Introducing the GitOps Approach</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/2023-12-11-gitops-intro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/2023-12-11-gitops-intro/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>When managing one or more clusters, the question arises as to how cluster configurations and applications can be installed securely, regularly, and in the same way.
This is where the so-called GitOps approach helps, according to the mantra: &amp;#34;&lt;strong>If it is not in Git, it does not exist&lt;/strong>&amp;#34;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>The idea is to have Git as the only source of truth on what happens inside the environment. While there are many articles about how to get GitOps into the deployment process of applications, this series of articles tries to set the focus on the &lt;strong>cluster configuration&lt;/strong> and tasks system administrators usually have to do, for example: Setup an Operator.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Quay Deployment and Configuration using GitOps</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2023-11-03-quay-deployment-with-gitops/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2023-11-03-quay-deployment-with-gitops/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Installing and configuring Quay Enterprise using a GitOps approach is not as easy as it sounds.
On the one hand, the operator is deployed easily, on the other hand, the configuration of Quay is quite tough to do in a declarative way and syntax rules must be strictly followed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>In this article, I am trying to explain how I solved this issue by using a Kubernetes Job and a Helm Chart.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Operator installation with Argo CD</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2023-03-20-operator-installation-with-argocd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2023-03-20-operator-installation-with-argocd/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>GitOps for application deployment and cluster configuration is a must-have I am trying to convince every customer to follow from the very beginning when starting the Kubernetes journey. For me, as more on the infrastructure side of things, I am more focused on the configuration of an environment.
Meaning, configuring a cluster, installing an operator etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>In this article, I would like to share how I deal with cluster configuration when certain Kubernetes objects are dependent on each other and how to use Kubernetes but also Argo CD features to resolve these dependencies.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Using ServerSideApply with ArgoCD</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2022-11-04-argocd-and-serversideapply/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2022-11-04-argocd-and-serversideapply/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>„&lt;em>If it is not in GitOps, it does not exist&lt;/em>“ - However, managing objects partially only by Gitops was always an issue, since ArgoCD would like to manage the whole object. For example, when you tried to work with node labels and would like to manage them via Gitops, you would need to put the whole node object into ArgoCD. This is impractical since the node object is very complex and typically managed by the cluster.
There were 3rd party solutions (like the patch operator), that helped with this issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>However, with the Kubernetes feature &lt;strong>Server-Side Apply&lt;/strong> this problem is solved. Read further to see a working example of this feature.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>GitOps - Argo CD</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2020-08-06-argocd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2020-08-06-argocd/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://argoproj.github.io/argo-cd/">Argo CD&lt;/a> &lt;em>is a declarative, GitOps continuous delivery tool for Kubernetes. GitOps itself uses Git pull request to manager infrastructure and application configuration.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>YAUB Yet Another Useless Blog</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/</guid><description>Welcome to YAUB - Yet Another Useless Blog The articles in this blog shall help to easily test and understand specific issues so they can be reproduced and tested on local environments.
You can find the most recent posts on this site or walk through the different categories via the left navigation.</description></item></channel></rss>