<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Gitops on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/tags/gitops/</link><description>Recent content in Gitops on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Toni Schmidbauer &amp; Thomas Jungbauer</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.stderr.at/tags/gitops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Operator installation with Argo CD</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2023-03-20-operator-installation-with-argocd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2023-03-20-operator-installation-with-argocd/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>GitOps for application deployment and cluster configuration is a must-have I am trying to convince every customer to follow from the very beginning when starting the Kubernetes journey. For me, as more on the infrastructure side of things, I am more focused on the configuration of an environment.
Meaning, configuring a cluster, installing an operator etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>In this article, I would like to share how I deal with cluster configuration when certain Kubernetes objects are dependent on each other and how to use Kubernetes but also Argo CD features to resolve these dependencies.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Using ServerSideApply with ArgoCD</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2022-11-04-argocd-and-serversideapply/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2022-11-04-argocd-and-serversideapply/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>„&lt;em>If it is not in GitOps, it does not exist&lt;/em>“ - However, managing objects partially only by Gitops was always an issue, since ArgoCD would like to manage the whole object. For example, when you tried to work with node labels and would like to manage them via Gitops, you would need to put the whole node object into ArgoCD. This is impractical since the node object is very complex and typically managed by the cluster.
There were 3rd party solutions (like the patch operator), that helped with this issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>However, with the Kubernetes feature &lt;strong>Server-Side Apply&lt;/strong> this problem is solved. Read further to see a working example of this feature.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>GitOps - Argo CD</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2020-08-06-argocd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2020-08-06-argocd/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://argoproj.github.io/argo-cd/">Argo CD&lt;/a> &lt;em>is a declarative, GitOps continuous delivery tool for Kubernetes. GitOps itself uses Git pull request to manager infrastructure and application configuration.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>