<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Authentication on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/tags/authentication/</link><description>Recent content in Authentication on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Toni Schmidbauer &amp; Thomas Jungbauer</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 09:11:48 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.stderr.at/tags/authentication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Advanced Cluster Security</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/acs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/acs/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Single log out from Keycloak and OpenShift</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2025/05/single-log-out-from-keycloak-and-openshift/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2025/05/single-log-out-from-keycloak-and-openshift/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>The following 1-minute article is a follow-up to my &lt;a href="https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2025/05/step-by-step-using-keycloak-authentication-in-openshift/">previous article&lt;/a> about how to use Keycloak as an authentication provider for OpenShift. In this article, I will show you how to configure Keycloak and OpenShift for Single Log Out (SLO). This means that when you log out from Keycloak, you will also be logged out from OpenShift automatically. This requires some additional configuration in Keycloak and OpenShift, but it is not too complicated.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Step by Step - Using Keycloak Authentication in OpenShift</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2025/05/step-by-step-using-keycloak-authentication-in-openshift/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2025/05/step-by-step-using-keycloak-authentication-in-openshift/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>I was recently asked about how to use Keycloak as an authentication provider for OpenShift. How to install Keycloak using the Operator and how to configure Keycloak and OpenShift so that users can log in to OpenShift using OpenID.
I have to admit that the exact steps are not easy to find, so I decided to write a blog post about it, describing each step in detail.
This time I will not use GitOps, but the OpenShift and Keycloak Web Console to show the steps, because before we put it into GitOps, we need to understand what is actually happening.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>This article tries to explain every step required so that a user can authenticate to OpenShift using Keycloak as an Identity Provider (IDP) and that Groups from Keycloak are imported into OpenShift. This article does not cover a production grade installation of Keycloak, but only a test installation, so you can see how it works. For production, you might want to consider a proper database (maybe external, but at least with a backup), high availability, etc.).&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Advanced Cluster Security - Authentication</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/acs/2021-12-11-acsauth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/acs/2021-12-11-acsauth/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Red Hat Advanced Cluster Security (RHACS) Central is installed with one administrator user by default. Typically, customers request an integration with existing Identity Provider(s) (IDP). RHACS offers different options for such integration. In this article 2 IDPs will be configured as an example. First OpenShift Auth and second Red Hat Single Sign On (RHSSO) based on Keycloak&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Automation Controller and LDAP Authentication</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/ansible/2021/10/automation-controller-and-ldap-authentication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/ansible/2021/10/automation-controller-and-ldap-authentication/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>The following article shall quickly, without huge background information, deploy an Identity Management Server (based on FreeIPA) and connect this IDM to an existing Automation Controller so authentication can be tested and verified based on LDAP.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>