<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Operator on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/tags/operator/</link><description>Recent content in Operator on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Toni Schmidbauer &amp; Thomas Jungbauer</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 15:10:12 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.stderr.at/tags/operator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What's New</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/whatss-new/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/whatss-new/</guid><description/></item><item><title>OpenShift</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Quay</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/quay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/quay/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Operator installation with Argo CD</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2023/03/operator-installation-with-argo-cd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2023/03/operator-installation-with-argo-cd/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>GitOps for application deployment and cluster configuration is a must-have I am trying to convince every customer to follow from the very beginning when starting the Kubernetes journey. For me, as more on the infrastructure side of things, I am more focused on the configuration of an environment.
Meaning, configuring a cluster, installing an operator etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>In this article, I would like to share how I deal with cluster configuration when certain Kubernetes objects are dependent on each other and how to use Kubernetes but also Argo CD features to resolve these dependencies.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Writing Operator using Ansible</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2021/01/writing-operator-using-ansible/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/openshift/2021/01/writing-operator-using-ansible/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>This quick post shall explain, without any fancy details, how to write an Operator based on Ansible. It is assumed that you know what purpose an Operator has.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>As a short summary: Operators are a way to create custom controllers in OpenShift or Kubernetes. It watches for custom resource objects and creates the application based on the parameters in such custom resource object.
Often written in &lt;strong>Go&lt;/strong>, the SDK supports &lt;strong>Ansible&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Helm&lt;/strong> and (new) &lt;strong>Java&lt;/strong> as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>YAUB Yet Another Useless Blog</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/</guid><description>&lt;h1 class="blog-title gradient-header">Welcome to Yet Another Useless Blog&lt;/h1>


&lt;p>Well we hope the articles here are not totally useless :)&lt;/p>

&lt;p>Who are we, you might ask.
We (Thomas Jungbauer and Toni Schmidbauer) are two old IT guys, working in the business since more than 20 years. At the moment we are architects at Red Hat Austria, mainly responsible helping customers with OpenShift or Ansible architectures. &lt;/p>

&lt;p>The articles in this blog shall help to easily test and understand specific issues so they can be reproduced and tested. We simply wrote down what we saw in the field and of what we thought it might be helpful, so no frustrating searches in documentations or manual testing is required. &lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>