<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SBOM on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/tags/sbom/</link><description>Recent content in SBOM on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Toni Schmidbauer &amp; Thomas Jungbauer</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 06:59:13 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.stderr.at/tags/sbom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Secure Supply Chain</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/securesupplychain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/securesupplychain/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Introduction to a Secure Supply Chain</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/securesupplychain/2023-06-15-securesupplychain-intro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/securesupplychain/2023-06-15-securesupplychain-intro/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>The goal of the following (&amp;#34;short&amp;#34;) series is to build a secure CI/CD pipeline step by step using OpenShift Pipelines (based on Tekton).
The whole build process shall pull and build an image, upload it to a development environment and subsequently update the production environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>The main focus here is security. Several steps and tools shall help to build and deploy a &lt;strong>Secure Supply Chain&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>The whole process is part of a Red Hat workshop which can present to your organization. I did some tweaks and created a step-by-step plan in order
to remember it …​ since I am getting old :)&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Step 7 - Generating a SBOM</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/securesupplychain/2023-06-22-securesupplychain-step7/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/securesupplychain/2023-06-22-securesupplychain-step7/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>software bill of materials&lt;/strong> (SBOM) offers an insight into the makeup of an application developed using third-party commercial tools and open-source software. It is a machine-readable, formally structured list of all components. This list is important to gain visibility into what risks might exist in a package and their potential impact. It allows to prioritize the risks and define a remediation path.
The teams can use the SBOM to monitor all components that are used across an application.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>We will create a Task that will generate a SBOM and uploads it into an SBOM repository.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>YAUB Yet Another Useless Blog</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/</guid><description>Welcome to Yet Another Useless Blog Well we hope the articles here are not totally useless.
Who are we, you might ask. We (Thomas Jungbauer and Toni Schmidbauer) are two old IT guys, working in the business since more than 20 years (each or us). At the moment we are architects at Red Hat Austria, mainly responsible helping customers with OpenShift or Ansible architecture.
The articles in this blog shall help to easily test and understand specific issues so they can be reproduced and tested.</description></item></channel></rss>