<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stackrox on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/tags/stackrox/</link><description>Recent content in Stackrox on TechBlog about OpenShift/Ansible/Satellite and much more</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Toni Schmidbauer &amp; Thomas Jungbauer</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 16:53:45 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.stderr.at/tags/stackrox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Advanced Cluster Security</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/acs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/acs/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Setup &amp; Configure Advanced Cluster Security using GitOps</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/2024-04-28-installing-advanced-cluster-security/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/gitopscollection/2024-04-28-installing-advanced-cluster-security/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Today I want to demonstrate the deployment and configuration of &lt;strong>Advanced Cluster Security&lt;/strong> (ACS) using a GitOps approach. The required operator shall be installed, verified if it is running and then ACS shall be initialized. This initialization contains the deployment of several components:&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="olist arabic">
&lt;ol class="arabic">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Central - as UI and as a main component of ACS&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>SecuredClusters - installs a Scanner, Controller pods etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Console link into OpenShift UI - to directly access the ACS Central UI&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Job to create an initialization bundle to install the Secured Cluster&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Job to configure authentication using OpenShift&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Let’s start …​&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Advanced Cluster Security - Authentication</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/acs/2021-12-11-acsauth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/acs/2021-12-11-acsauth/</guid><description>&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Red Hat Advanced Cluster Security (RHACS) Central is installed with one administrator user by default. Typically, customers request an integration with existing Identity Provider(s) (IDP). RHACS offers different options for such integration. In this article 2 IDPs will be configured as an example. First OpenShift Auth and second Red Hat Single Sign On (RHSSO) based on Keycloak&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>YAUB Yet Another Useless Blog</title><link>https://blog.stderr.at/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.stderr.at/</guid><description>&lt;h1 class="blog-title gradient-header">Welcome to Yet Another Useless Blog&lt;/h1>


&lt;p>Well we hope the articles here are not totally useless :)&lt;/p>

&lt;p>Who are we, you might ask.
We (Thomas Jungbauer and Toni Schmidbauer) are two old IT guys, working in the business since more than 20 years. At the moment we are architects at Red Hat Austria, mainly responsible helping customers with OpenShift or Ansible architectures. &lt;/p>

&lt;p>The articles in this blog shall help to easily test and understand specific issues so they can be reproduced and tested. We simply wrote down what we saw in the field and of what we thought it might be helpful, so no frustrating searches in documentations or manual testing is required. &lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>